Ryan Knight

Software Developer

Salt Lake City , UT (509) - 690- 7778 ryan.knight09@outlook.com

About me

I have been writing software for roughly five years and consider myself a front end developer. I like to think I am a full stack front end developer due to my ability to build robust javascript backend servers(gqI, express) as well as my React development experience. I love UI kits like material UI since I am not a ninja on hard core HTLM/ CSS design but I can certainly handle anything in the realm. For the last three years I have been all about GraphqI and React.

Experience

April 2019-Present

Front End Developer - StorageCraft Technology Corp.

Front end project lead for Saas Cloud Backup and Recovery for O365, G-suit. Responsibilities include architecting Graphql data server, and React client. Client stack: React, React Router, Jest, Apollo Client 3 (comprehensive data layer solution: fetching, caching, state management). GQL server stack: (Apollo, express, jest, firebase / firestore / real time database).

June 2018 - March 2019

Software Engineering Intern - Exact Sciences Laboratory Information Systems

My main role was to work on code optimizations inside of our application as well as building automated QA test environment features for our business analysts. Most of my development was in Java, Javascript, and various JS frameworks such as React.

Sep 2017 - 2018

Teaching Assistant - Eastern Washington University

Tutoring and grading student assignments in the Java development courses.

Education

Sept 2015 - 2019

Eastern Washington University - Cheney , Wa - B.S Computer Science

- Heavy emphasis on OOP in Java, relational database, data structure ect.
- Web development with React

Sept 2009 - June 2011

Spokane Falls Community College - Spokane, Wa - AAS Audio Engineering

Extensive background in sound production, signal processing, system hardware design set up, and post production.

Projects

Washington State DSHS Adult Family Home Facilities Smart Scheduler: (.Net)

A native GUI application with an algorithm to determine home inspection schedules based off of prior data of the facility. I am the lead developer on the Database / backend business logic. Persistence is done with Object Relational Mapping using Entity Framework Core.

Happy Camper Web App: (CSS, HTML5, Javascript, Node.js Express, Mongodb)

Fairly old and outdated project. A responsive and dynamic web application for campsite reviews. The application handles login authentication, and flash messaging for user feedback. Data association is utilized so that users own the campsites and comment posts they create. github.com/ryanknight09/HappyCamper

I would be happy to discuss my current work and skill set within the Apollo stack and React. Some areas are under NDA therefore not public, however I can show some work on demo branches.

References

Professional references available upon request please.